Falaah Alshammari

+96

+966534719999

•

Falaah_alshammari@hotmail.com
Falaah Alshammari



Dammam, Saudi Arabia

Objective

Dedicated and reliable Senior Project Engineer, with 5+ years of experience in Electric Power industry including Infrastructure, Construction and Operation/ Maintenance fields. Looking to secure a position with an innovative and challenging organization, which allows for professional growth where I can maximize my abilities for the betterment of the company and reaching its objectives.

Education

Master's Degree in Engineering Management

King Fahad University of Petroleum and Minerals (Dhahran, Saudi Arabia) | 2020 - 2022

Cumulative GPA: 3.9 out of 4 (First hounor degree)

Bachelor's Degree in Electrical Engineering (Power and Energy Systems)

University of Manitoba - Manitoba, Canada (King Abdullah Foreign Scholarship) | 2010 - 2016

Cumulative GPA: 3.4 out of 4

Experience

Senior Project Engineer | Legrand Company | Dec 2018 - Present

- . Work closely with project engineers and other project professionals to provide work direction and guidance.
- Participate in the review and evaluation of the capabilities of the contractors, suppliers, and project management-related service providers.
- Provide expert advice and guidance in project planning, execution, and control.
- Assist in resolving project management problems related to the area of expertise, including project planning deficiencies, project quality defects (in engineering, procurement, or construction), schedule slippages, and potential cost overruns.
- Work with Key End User, ARAMCO, RC, SABIC, SEC, MINISTRIES, TARSHID, TBC...etc.
- Participate in key projects across the kingdom, King Salman Global Maritime Industries Complex | Neom Airport Saudi Aramco Dhahran Data Center | King Abdullah Financial District...Etc.
- Work with +100 Contractor, +20 Consultant, +30 Designer, +10 System Integrator and +10 Distributors.
- Contribute to the company profit of +20M SAR from supplying electrical materials to projects.
- Formulate and implement strategies to improve project planning, cost, schedule, and quality.
- Lead internal or external problem-solving teams as directed by management.
- · Conduct training courses in the area of expertise.
- Participate in the development of standards, guidelines, instructions, policies, and procedures on an as-required basis.

Project Engineer | Al-Babtain Power and Telecom | Oct 2016 - Oct 2018

- · Prepare, schedule, coordinate, and monitoring of assigned engineering projects.
- · Formulate project parameters and assign responsibilities to the most capable employees and monitor the project team.
- · Interact with clients, interpret their needs and requirements, and represent them in the field.
- Perform quality control tasks on budgets, schedules, plans, and personnel performance and report on the project's status.
- Cooperate and communicate with the project manager and other project participants and collaborate with senior engineers to create more efficient project methods and maintain the project's profitability.
- Review the engineering tasks and initiate the necessary corrective actions.
- · Develop specifications for the project's needed equipment.
- · Create frameworks to measure the project's metrics and data collection.
- Establish field test methods and methods for monitoring the quality of those tests.
- Ensure the project's compliance with the applicable codes, practices, policies, performance standards, and specifications.

Electrical Instrumentation Technician | Saudi Electricity Company | Sep 2004 - Apr 2009

- Use gauges and other test instruments to diagnose malfunctions and mechanic hand and power tools to disassemble, repair, and reassemble system components.
- Manage and maintain instrument calibration documentation.
- Perform work requiring a thorough knowledge of instrument application, operation, and the electrical and mechanical principles involved in repair, testing, and calibration.
- Participate in the planning and execution of minor and major shutdowns.
- · Assist in the development and ongoing improvement of the plant mechanical integrity program.

Skills

- · Project Engineer
- Quality Management
- Data Analysis
- Performance Monitoring
- Strategic Planning
- Critical Thinking
- Technical Support
- Cost Estimation
- · Technical Support
- · Electrical Systems
- · Preventive Maintenance

- · Process Control Systems
- · Safety Regulation
- · Report Management
- Research
- · Service Orientation
- · Technological Aptitude
- · Microsoft Office
- · Problems Troubleshooting
- Accuracy
- Effective Communication
- Teamwork

Certificates

• Project Management Professional (PMP)® | Saudi Council of Engineers (SCE)

Key Projects

- · King Salman Global Maritime Industries Complex
- · Chambers of Commerce Tower
- · Saudi Aramco Dhahran Data Center
- · King Abdullah Financial District
- · Dr. Sulaiman AlHabib Hospital
- Participated in many international hotel projects | Ministry of Housing Project | Tarshid Projects

Appreciation

- First Honor Degree | Faculty of Engineering, KFUPM, Dhahran, Saudi Arabia | 2022
- Deans Honor List | Faculty of Engineering, University of Manitoba, Winnipeg, Canada | 2012 & 2015